http://scholarships.com/about-us/privacy-policy/

Last updated: June 9, 2020
This Privacy Policy applies to www.scholarships.com. This Privacy Policy describes how Scholarships.com collects and uses the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information.
Scholarships.com recognizes that your privacy is important. To demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy and to explain the types of information we obtain about visitors to our website, how that information is obtained and used, and how visitors can restrict its use or disclosure, we have created the Privacy Policy below. The following discusses our information gathering and dissemination practices at Scholarships.com.
Information We Receive and How It Is Used
All personal information obtained by Scholarships.com about individual visitors to our website is information supplied voluntarily by that visitor. During registration, users are required to provide certain categories of information, such as name, address, email address, phone number, a password, date of birth, gender, and country of citizenship. In addition, users may choose to provide other categories of information, such as career objectives, health or disability information, hobbies, and other interests. Scholarships.com encourages users to provide all fields of information to maximize the effectiveness of the scholarship and college search. We ask for permission when sharing information with marketing partners, which are reputable companies and organizations that provide products and services of interest to students and parents. Users may choose whether to opt-in or opt-out of sharing information with our marketing partners.
When Scholarships.com shares personal information with a third party, the information will become permanently subject to the information use and sharing practices of the third party. The third party will not be restricted by our Privacy Policy, with respect to its use and further sharing of your personal information. If you agree to receive communications from our marketing partners and later change your mind, you will need to contact those companies directly. Any information updates you wish to make must be forwarded to the company at that point in time.
Upon request Scholarships.com will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information.
Users may change personal profile information at Scholarships.com at any time by logging in to the website and entering the email address and password associated with their profile. After users have logged in, they will be directed to their Scholarship Matches. In the tabbed navigation at the top of the page, users will find a link to "Profile". By clicking on that tab, users will be directed to a summary of their information, divided into sections. An "Edit This Section" option in the upper-right corner of each section allows users to modify and update their information. Users can also contact us here in order to request access to submitted information. To protect the security and integrity of our users’ information, we will take necessary steps in verifying all new profile identities before providing access. It is the responsibility of the user to make all necessary changes in their profile and make sure their profiles are up-to-date.
Users of Scholarships.com who wish to terminate their membership, or otherwise request to cease usage of their information at Scholarships.com may do so at any time by contacting us via our contact form by clicking here. Please be sure to type "Remove" in the subject field and submit the email account associated with the membership you would like terminated. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. Information will be retained for as long as the account is active or requests our services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Scholarships.com is committed to safeguarding users' privacy on our website. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received.
We require our employees to protect our users and visitors by keeping their profile information private, and expect our marketing partners to follow suit. Rest assured that your user profile will be protected when you visit Scholarships.com. There are security measures to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of all user information under our control.
Regardless of whether you wish to share your personal information, we reserve the right to share aggregated demographic data and related information with our business partners. Such aggregate information will not contain any personal information that can identify any individual user.
Information Sharing & Email Preferences
Scholarships.com understands the importance of protecting personally-identifiable information. We will not share, sell, rent or otherwise transfer any information without the user's permission, and then, only in accordance with the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy. Our website provides users the opportunity to unsubscribe/opt-out from receiving email messages from Scholarships.com and its marketing partners, or from having their personal information shared with our marketing partners. Users may change their email preferences by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in each of the email messages they receive or by clicking here. Please allow up to seven business days for these changes to take effect. If you no longer wish to be a registered user of Scholarships.com, you may have your profile removed by clicking here.
Scholarships.com may periodically use contact information in order to send emails regarding updates at the Scholarships.com site, such as scholarship opportunities and additional listings. The frequency of these messages will vary depending on the user's preference, including the types of scholarships and other activities in which a user has indicated an interest. If you specifically provide Scholarships.com with permission at the time of registration, you may also receive commercial emails. Please note that email messages from third parties are not governed by the opt-out provisions of this Privacy Policy.
In certain situations, Scholarships.com may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities.
We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process. When we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.
We may provide your personal information to company provider services that help us with business-related activity; such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only on a service-needs basis.
California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)
Scholarships.com is working in full cooperation with the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA). If you’ve reviewed Scholarships.com’s Privacy Policy, you know you have certain rights regarding your personal information. Scholarships.com collects and shares data with our marketing partners in an effort to maintain our free site and services. The recently enacted California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) offers California residents the right to opt-out of the sale of their personal information and you can do that by, clicking here.
Scholarships.com shares your information with a variety of third-party entities. Among the myriad benefits of using Scholarships.com is your ability to interact with scholarship providers and also to be recruited by colleges and universities and others related to the college admissions and financial aid process. When you opt to interact with these third-parties, our website passes your information along to them so that they are able to provide more information to you about their scholarship, financial aid, institutional and other programs and offerings.
On occasion, Scholarships.com may also provide your personal information to advertisers and other marketing partners who are interested in marketing to your specific demographic in exchange for fees or other consideration. If you do not want us to sell your information as defined by CCPA, we encourage you to opt-out of such sales of your information by completing the form below. Also, if you are a California resident under 16 years of age, we will not sell your information as defined by CCPA unless you opt-in at the time you create a Scholarships.com account or at another time that you choose to allow us to sell your information.
Collection of Passive Information
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.
We, Scholarships.com, and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.
Some of our business partners, such as advertisers, use cookies on our site, but we have neither access to, nor control over, these cookies. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Scholarships.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by our business partners
We partner with a third party ad network to display advertising on our web site. Our ad network partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for targeting ads, you may opt-out by clicking here. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.
We use Google AdSense to publish ads on this site. When you view or click on an ad a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on this and other web sites. You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google’s Advertising and Privacy page: http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.
We may share statistical and demographic information about our website's visitors with our marketing partners. This information is only provided in the aggregate; meaning that the information is about our website's visitors as a group and not about individually-identifiable visitors.
Public Forums
Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. Please be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, you may contact us by clicking here. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information. In these situations, we will provide you with an explanation.
Social Media Features
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, page visitation on the site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.
Links to Other Websites
Scholarships.com contains text and banner links to other sites. Scholarships.com does not exercise control over the information, products, services or policies of third party companies accessible through our site. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collected by this site
Collection of Information from Children
Scholarships.com abides by federal law and the guidelines set up by the Federal Trade Commission regarding youth privacy. As such, Scholarships.com will not knowingly collect any personally-identifiable information from children under the age of 13, nor will children under the age of 13 be allowed to register with Scholarships.com.
Notification of Changes
If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email prior to the effective change. You may decide whether or not we can use your information in this manner. In addition, if we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change. In cases where we post notice of changes, we may also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes to our privacy practices.
In the event that Scholarships.com sells, signs or transfers some or all of its business to a successor or acquirer, Scholarships.com may sell, assign or transfer all of your information, regardless of your opt status, to such successor or acquirer.
Testimonials
We post user testimonials on our website, all of which are volunteered and none of which contain individually-identifiable information beyond the user's first name, last initial, and photograph. Each user is made aware of the purpose of their supplied testimonial that it will be published on Scholarships.com. Users are under no obligation to participate, and we obtain the user's consent prior to posting this information. If you have any questions about a testimonial you can contact us by clicking here.
Scholarships.com has adopted privacy principles that state our commitment and define policy on safeguarding visitor and user privacy when conducting business. Questions regarding this Privacy Policy statement, the practices of this website, or dealings with Scholarships.com should be directed to Scholarships.com's privacy department. Alternatively, you may contact us at:
Privacy at Scholarships.com
Scholarships.com, LLC
430 Park Avenue, Suite 3A
Highland Park, IL 60035
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) athttps://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request
ADVERTISEMENT
ADVERTISEMENT
Latest College & Financial Aid News
Celebrate Hanukkah with Eight Jewish Scholarships
December 10, 2020
by
Izzy Hall
Tonight is the first night of Hanukkah, the eight-day festival of lights celebrated each winter by Jewish families. During Hanukkah, menorahs are lit, latkes are fried, dreidels are spun and chocolate coins are eaten. If you’re celebrating Hanukkah this year, take some time to apply to these eight Jewish scholarships – one for each night! You’ll give yourself a chance to win a “present” of free financial aid for college. [...]
University Teams up with Local Brewer to Offer Minority Scholarship
December 8, 2020
by
Izzy Hall
Sacred Heart University has teamed up with the New England Brewing Co., an original Connecticut craft brewery, to offer a full-ride scholarship to a Black student interested in completing the university’s brewing science certificate program. This new scholarship will cover the costs of SHU’s one-year certificate program that teaches students all the skills needed to enter the craft brewing industry, from business management to brewing science.
[...]
The College Experience in a “Resort Bubble”?
December 3, 2020
by
Izzy Hall
The coronavirus pandemic has changed our perspective on education. Online education, quarantine dorms and virtual campuses have been broadly implemented in the COVID era. In the midst of this education shakeup, some businesses have begun to offer alternatives to both traditional college and our current pandemic-flavor of education. The U Experience is one such venture that promises a small number of students a mask-free, COVID-free resort campus where they can take online classes.
[...]
